Guide to the Joe David Bellamy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 2007 Acquisition, 1962-2007; 3; 16.67; (19 boxes, including 1 computer disk)
  - Writings By Others, 1971-2001
    - "Saturday Night in Baoding" mansucript, by Richard Terrill, circa 1990 (Box 72)
    - "Science Fiction: Contemporary Myth-makers" manuscript, edited by P. Warrick, M. Greenberg, and J. Olander, 1977; 3 (Box 72)
    - "Importal Life" manuscript, by Mike West, 1999 (Box 72)
    - "Under the Gaze of Hercules" manuscript, by Eldonna Ruddock, 1999; 2 (Box 72)
    - Litany for a Vanishing Landscape, by Wayne Sides and Jeanie Thompson, 1990 (Box 72)
    - "Eye of the Blackbird" manuscript, by Mary Ann McFadden, 1997 (Box 72)
    - "Splendide-Hotel", 1973 (Box 72)
    - "The Psychic takes a Greyhound" manuscript, by Susan Hubbard, 1999; 2 (Box 72)
    - "The View from the End of the World" manuscript, by Laurie Alberts, 1996; 5 (Box 72)
    - "The View from the End of the World" manuscript, by Laurie Alberts (continued), 1996; 2 (Box 73)
    - "Driving the Boss Lady" manuscript, by Roger Parham-Brown, 6 (Box 73)
    - "Well-Founded Fear" manuscript, by Tom LeClair, 2000 (Box 73)
  - Professional Papers, circa 1970s-2006
    - Random House Envelopes, 2006 (Box 73)
    - Possible Reading Dates, circa 1978 (Box 73)
    - Propaganda for Readings, 1970 (Box 73)
    - Recommendations, circa 1980 (Box 73)
    - St. Lawrence Correspondence, circa 1980s -1994 (Box 73)
    - Iowa International Writing Program, circa 1982-1989 (Box 73)
    - Job Applications, circa 1978-1995; 2 (Box 73)
    - Rejection Letters, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 73)
    - Rejection letters, circa 1970s-1990s; 5 (Box 74)
  - Other Papers, 1969-1980
    - Yachting Magazine, 1977 (Box 75)
    - Boating Magazine, 1977 (Box 75)
    - Duke Reunion Information and Curtis F. Bellamy Obituary, 1969-1973 (Box 75)
    - Religious Satire (Box 75)
    - Publishers Weekly Magazine (annotated), 1980 (Box 75)
    - Motorboat Magazine, 1977 (Box 75)
    - 1959 Class Reunion, 1979 (Box 75)
    - Religious Writing and Various Material, circa 1975 (Box 75)
    - Duke University Material, circa 1974 (Box 75)
    - Business card of publisher Bill Henderson with a note; removed from Gerber, Merrill Joan. King of the World: a Novel. Wainscott, NY: Pushcart Press, 1989, undated (Box 75)
  - Audiocassettes, circa 1970s-
    - Long Interview with Colin Harrison and Kathryn Harrison (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 2000 October 25 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246711)
      A note describes a small portion of the long interview appeared in The Iowa Review in 2007. Most of it (about 100 [?] pages) were never published.
    - Long interview with Colin Harrison and Kathryn Harrison (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246729)
    - WSLU Interview, circa 1970s; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246554)
    - The Lost Saranac Interviews, (13 audiocassettes)
      - Russell Banks, Eng 310, 1983 November 7; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246596)
      - Russell Banks, Eng 241, 1983 November 8; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246588)
      - Annie Dillard / Jayne Anne Phillips, Saranac, 1978, 1979; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246604)
      - E. L. Doctorow, Saranac, 1979; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246612)
      - Magazine Panel, Saranac, 1977; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246620)
      - JC Oates at Saranac, 1977 June; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246638)
      - Margaret Atwood, Saranac, 1978; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246646)
      - Atwood / Dillard / Brown, 1978; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246653)
      - Gail Godwin at Saranac, 1977 June; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246661)
      - Pitfalls of First Novels, undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246679)
      - Godwin & Hawkes, Saranac, 1976; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246687)
      - Ann Beattie at Saranac, 1977; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246695)
      - Moral Fiction Panel, Saranac, 1979; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246703)
    - Early interview of President Frank P. Piskor (St. Lawrence University), Toe Technique #1 (1 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246562)
    - Early interview of President Frank P. Piskor (St. Lawrence University) regarding his collection of [?] 1st editions of American poets (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002091246570)
  - Computer media
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copy of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - photo slide show from fiction international/St. Lawrence Univ. Writers Conference, 1974-79, 2007-ycal-11018-0001; 1 (Box 77)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- May 2014 Acquisition, 1970-2014; 4; 0.67; (2 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Joe David Bellamy, 2014.
  This addition consists of correspondence, writings, printed material, photobooks, electronic files, and other papers by or relating to Joe David Bellamy.
  - Correspondence, 2007-2014; 27 (Box 78)
    Includes email, instant messages, and other correspondence with Steve Amick, Rilla Askew, Russell Banks, Fredrick Barthelme, Elizabeth Benedict, Doris Betts, Kelly Cherry, Alam Cheuse, Robb Forman Dew, John Domini, Constance Daniels Graves, Bill Henderson, William Hjortsberg, Josephine Humphreys, Tom Jenkes, Wally Lamb, Kerry Langen, Roger Lathbury, Stanley Plumly, Reynolds Price, Beth Raymer, Ishmael Reed, Alberto Rios, James Robison, Anne Sanow, Belinda Susan Webb, and Rob Wilson.
  - Writings and related materials, 2011-2014 (Box 78)
    Includes writings, reviews, and with related correspondence.
  - Ephemera and miscellaneous materials, 1970-2012 (Box 78)
    Includes ticket stubs, correspondence with editors, and teaching materials.
  - Family photo books, circa 2000-2014; 2 (Box 78)
  - Electronic media, circa 2000-2012 (Box 79)